<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on Pram&#39;s</title>
    <link>https://aryapramudika.com/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on Pram&#39;s</description>
    <image>
      <title>Pram&#39;s</title>
      <url>https://aryapramudika.com/papermod-cover.png</url>
      <link>https://aryapramudika.com/papermod-cover.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2023 21:28:16 +0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://aryapramudika.com/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Install &amp; Build Cluster with Pacemaker, Corosync, pcs on Centos/Alma/RHEL 9</title>
      <link>https://aryapramudika.com/blog/pacemaker/install/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2023 21:28:16 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aryapramudika.com/blog/pacemaker/install/</guid>
      <description>Pacemaker &amp;amp; Corosync is popular stack for High Avaibility on Linux Servers, since 2004.
Pacemaker is a high-availability cluster resource manager – software that runs on a set of hosts (a cluster of nodes) in order to preserve btegrity and minimize downtime of desired services (resources).
Corosync is open source group communication system that provides ordered communication delivery, cluster membership, quorum enforcement, and other features among the nodes, it helps detect component failures and orchestrate necessary failover procedures to minimize interruptions to applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installasi Debian 10 Minimal Server</title>
      <link>https://aryapramudika.com/blog/installasi-debian10-minimal-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2023 20:24:00 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aryapramudika.com/blog/installasi-debian10-minimal-server/</guid>
      <description>Installasi Debian 10 Minimal Server Latar Belakang Masalah Saya sedang belajar tentang debian server, terutama debian CLI. Saya sering lupa konfigurasi awal saat installasi debian untuk itu saya membuat tulisan ini.
Tujuan Tujuan saya menulis ini yaitu sebagai catatan belajar, jika saya lupa sesuatu maka saya bisa membaca tulisan ini.
Persyaratan Untuk persyaratan installasi yaitu:
Mempunyai koneksi Internet untuk mendownload iso CD/DVD Debian 10.
Perangkat Laptop/PC bisa juga Virtual seperti VirtualBox/VMWare</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
